The State of Affairs
FIRE
So, I told my classmates…
(ユリト)だから 同期のやつらに
言ってやったんすよ～。
お前ら暇でいいなって。
that they were lucky to have
so much free time.
俺もここ来て
ひと月じゃないですか。
It's been a month since I got here.
Isn't it about time I get to supervise
a big assignment on my own?
そろそろ でかい案件→
任されても
いい頃じゃないっすかね？
(ユリト)ああ 火影様。
Oh, Lord Hokage!
Where was yesterday's report again?
(カカシ)昨日の報告書って
どこだっけ？
Third pile to the right,
the second one.
(シカマル)３段目の右から２つ目です。
うん。
ああ これね
これってたしか 添付の資料が…。
Oh, here it is.
Didn't this come with
some attachments?
Second pile, the third one.
２段目の３つ目です。
お前がいてくれて助かるよ。
I don't know what
I'd do without you.
Oh right, Lord Hokage.
そうだ 火影様
来週の視察の件ですけど。
About next week's inspection…
I keep telling you to
just call me Kakashi.
カカシさんでいいって
何度言えばわかんの？
You're way too stiff
and formal, senpai!
肩に力 入りすぎっすよ 先輩。
And don't forget to take a break.
それと 休憩もとってよね
能率落ちちゃうからさ。
Efficiency gets compromised
if you don't.
了解っす。
Roger!
ふぁ～ しっかし
デスクワークするために→
Anyway…
I didn't become a shinobi
to be chained to a desk.
忍になったんじゃない
っつうんですよ。
先輩
こんな退屈な仕事ばっかで→
How do you not get bored
doing this sort of work, senpai?
よく飽きないっすね。 先輩？
Uh, senpai?
雲を見るのも久しぶりだな。
I haven't looked up at the clouds
in a long time.
先輩って ときどき
オッサンみたいなこと言いますよね。
You know, senpai,
sometimes you talk like an old man.
先輩 何か
悩みごとでもあるんすか？
Is something bothering you?
Huh?
はあ？ ねえよ。
No.
これでよし。
And, I'm done for the day!
Man!
や～ 今日も楽勝でしたね
んじゃ お疲れっした～。
We cruised through today!
Thanks, and see ya tomorrow!
Oh, Lord Hokage!
ああ 火影様
お疲れっした～。
Thanks, and see ya tomorrow!
でした～。
See ya…
お疲れ。
Thanks for today.
なんで あんなやつ
採ったんすか？
Why'd you pick a guy like that?
大人の世界では
いろいろあるんだよ。
The adult world is complicated.
俺 そういうの苦手っす。
I don't like that kind of stuff.
あれ？ シカマルも とっくに
こっちの人間かと思ってたけど。
Oh?
I thought you became
one of us a while back.
勘弁してくださいよ。
Give me a break!
Having more shinobi like him
just goes to show we're at peace.
でも 彼みたいな忍が増えるのも
平和になった証しかもね。
あれから２年っすからね。
It's been two years since then.
I'm starting to get a belly…
俺 最近
下腹出てきちゃった。
聞きたくないっす。
I don't want to hear it.
シカマルは 今でも鍛えてる？
Do you keep up with training?
Here and there.
まあ テキト-に。
You say it like that,
そう言いながら どうせ
きっちりやってるんでしょ？
but I bet you're as
disciplined as ever.
かわいくないよ
そういうとこ。
Why can't you just
humor me a bit?
I told him to double-check it!
あいつ
二重チェックしろつったのに。
By the way, how is it going?
そういえば どうなってる？
例の件。
Regarding that issue.
待ちっすね。
連絡なしか。
It's on the back-burner.
No contact then?
お前に こんな役目を押し付けて
すまないと思ってる。
I feel bad burdening you
with it.
俺 もともと
忍には向いてないんすよ。
I was never really
cut out to be a shinobi.
The fact that
I continue to be one…
それでも続けてるのは…。
Is to make Naruto
the Hokage one day, right?
ナルトを
いずれ火影にするため だろ？
そのためには 俺もいつまでも
ガキじゃいられないんで。
To make sure that happens,
I can't be a child forever.
Naruto's still a child, even now.
ナルトは 今でもガキのまんまだ。
ヤツは ヤツです。
He is who he is.
Oh…
なあ それ終わったら→
How about we go grab
a bite after you're done?
久しぶりに
飯でもどうだ？
このあと 土影様と
これなんすよ。
After this, Lord Tsuchikage
and I have a game.
ハハ そういえば昨日
会議で会ったな。
Oh right, I saw him
at the conference yesterday.
今度こそ お前を負かすって
息巻いてたぞ。
All he talked about was how
he would beat you this time.
まあ お手柔らかに頼むよ。
Anyway, please go easy on him.
Well, half of it is work for me.
半分
仕事みたいなもんすから。
なあ シカマル→
Hey, Shikamaru…
大人になるって
どういうことなんだろうな？
I wonder what it means
to become an adult?
(オオノキ)む～。
うむ～ う～ん
いや違う こっちか？
No, wait… This one?
How's that, young 'un?
You're speechless now, eh?
どうじゃ 小僧？
ぐうの音も出まい ワッハッハ！
お？
Please excuse me…
では。
ええい！
Hey, don't think
I'll let you win and run!
勝ち逃げなど
許すものか～！
チッ… こりゃ
明日から倍だな。
Tsk…
I have to work twice
as hard tomorrow.
(みんな)お～！
HIDDEN LEAF LIBRARY
BARBE-Q
いらっしゃい！
Welcome!
(チョウジ)おっ 来た来た！
(いの)こっちよ。
Oh, there he is!
Over here!
遅れてすまない。
Sorry I'm late.
(チョウジ)それ 僕が育てた肉！
(シカマル)ハハッ はいよ。
That's the meat I was grilling!
Here you go.
こっちも焼けてるわよ。
おう。
This one's done too.
カルビ追加ね！
Another order of kalbi please!
Anyway, I keep teaching this newbie
and she just doesn't get it.
(いの)でね その新人の子が
何度教えても直んなくてさ～。
僕の班にも１人いるけど→
There's one on my team too.
自分を見てるみたいで
放っとけないんだよね。
He reminds me of myself
and I just can't ignore him.
アスマも こんな気持だったのかなぁ。
I wonder if
Asuma felt this way.
２人とも もうすっかり教官だな。
You two have totally embraced
your roles as instructors.
シカマルだって 火影様の右腕でしょ。
Well, you're Lord Hokage's
right-hand man, aren't you?
けど お前らみたいに→
But I don't have anyone
under me to mentor.
下の面倒を見る根気
俺にはねえよ。
シカマルは 自分でやったほうが早い
ってタイプだもんね。
You're the type that prefers
to just do things yourself.
Being a loner suits me.
ひとりが性に合ってるんだ。
俺にとっては
お前らだけが特別なんだよ。
You two are the only ones
who are special to me.
なんかさ 昔が懐かしい。
I miss the old days.
まだ そんな歳じゃねえだろ。
Hey, we're not old enough
to be saying that.
だってさ
前は四六時中 一緒にいるのが→
Back then, it was normal for us
to be together 24/7.
当たり前だったでしょ。
Now, we have to set up
a time and date just to eat together.
でも今は
こうして一緒に食事するのも→
いちいち
約束しなきゃならないんだよ。
It's kinda sad, huh?
それって なんか寂しいよね。
大人になるってのはさ
そういうことかもしれねえよな。
Maybe that's what it means
to become an adult.
確かに…
シカマル 雰囲気変わったわよね。
That's for sure.
Your temperament's changed.
はぁ？ 勘違いだろ。
Huh? You've got to be kidding.
最近 めんどくせぇって
言わなくなったの 気づいてる？
Lately, you never say,
"what a drag."
Haven't you noticed?
そう… だっけ？
Really?
(シカマル)ごちそうさん。
(いの)ごちそうさま。
BARBE-Q
– Thanks for the food!
– Thank you!
レジでガムくれたよ。
They gave me gum when
I was at the register.
これ 懐かしくない？
Doesn't this bring
back memories?
GUM
Doesn't this bring
back memories?
これ 子供の頃 よく食べたよね。
I always chewed this
when I was a kid!
(いの)うわ 甘っ！
こんな甘かった？
Oh, it's so sweet!
Was it always this sweet?
(チョウジ)で 次どうする？
Okay, where to next?
あんた まだ食べるつもり？
You still wanna eat more?
焼肉のハシゴしようよ～。
Let's go BBQ hopping!
悪い 俺 帰るわ。
えぇ!?
Sorry, I have to go.
Huh?!
シカマル なんか気になってること
あるんじゃない？
Shikamaru…
Is something on your mind?
上の空っていうかさ。
Your mind seems
to be wandering.
別にねえよ。
It's nothing.
ただの出張だって 忍連合の。
I have to leave the village for work,
on Allied Shinobi business.
それって
テマリとかカンクロウとかも来るやつ？
Is it the same thing Temari
and Kankuro attend?
私らより
テマリのほうが大事ってか？
So Temari is more important
than us?
イテテテテ… 何の話だよ!?
Oww…
What're you talking about?
SAMURAI
(長十郎)よりいっそうの
発展を願うものであります。
SAMURAI
And so, we hope that
it grows even more.
以上で活動報告を終わりますが
他に何か ご質問は？
That concludes my activity report.
Are there any other questions?
(黒ツチ)大戦で大量に出た
失踪者リストの件だけど→
Regarding the long list of
missing persons after the Great War…
その後の捜索は どうなってるの？
How is the search going?
鋭意 調査中。
It's currently under investigation.
(オモイ)忍への依頼が ３期連続で
減少している点については？
How about the drop in shinobi requests
for three consecutive periods?
鋭意 調査中。
It's currently under investigation.
けどな この先も
依頼が減り続けるようなら→
You know, if it keeps dropping,
里の運営にも影響が…。
(シカマル)来月の会合には→
it'll affect how we administer
the villages.
We should have a more
detailed report by the next meeting.
更に詳しい報告書を
提出できると思います。
忍への依頼が
減っている点について→
I understand the view
危機的な見方もあることは
承知していますが→
that a decrease in requests
for shinobi poses a concern.
平和に代償が伴うことも
また事実です。
But remember,
this is a consequence of peace.
他に質問もないようですので→
If there are no more questions,
それでは皆さん また ひと月後に。
we'll meet again in one month.
(テマリ)おい！ 待てよ シカマル。
Hey! Wait, Shikamaru!
ハァ…。
テマリ 何か用か？
What's going on, Temari?
何か 隠してるんだろ？
You're hiding something, aren't you?
はぁ？ いきなり何だ？
ほらな。
Huh? What makes you say that?
See?
質問を質問で返すときは
やましいことがある証拠だ。
When you answer a question
with a question,
it's proof that something's up.
木ノ葉で何が起きてるんだ？
知らねえな。
What's going on in
the Hidden Leaf Village?
I don't know what
you're talking about.
私にも話せないことなのか？
It's something you can't talk
to me about?
だから何もねえよ。
I said there's nothing going on!
私が力になれることは
ないってことか？
So there's nothing I can help with?
ない。
そう…。
Nope.
I see…
なあ テマリ。
Hey, Temari…
俺も お前も
一応は里の代表って立場なんだ。
Both you and I are representatives
of our villages…
あんまり よそのことに
首を突っ込むのは…。
We shouldn't pry too much
into the other's—
なにしやがる！
見損なったよ あんた。
What the hell—?!
I misjudged you!
(カカシ)ハッハッハッ！
それで
親父さんを思い出したってのか？
So that's what made
you remember your old man.
えぇ 朝帰りして→
Yes.
He often got yelled at by
my mom for staying out all night.
よく おふくろに
怒鳴られてたもんで。
そいつは災難だったな。
Sorry you had to go through that.
テマリは勘のいいやつです。
Temari is very intuitive.
いずれはバレますよ 黙の国の件。
She's going to find out
sooner or later
about the Land of Silence.
大戦での失踪者や抜け忍が→
Many of the missing from
the Great War
大量に流れ込んでいるという
謎の国。
and Rogue Ninja are filtering
into this mysterious land.
そして 忍の依頼を
不法に請け負っている黒い噂。
And there's a deep, dark rumor
that it's undertaking
shinobi missions illegally.
本来なら 忍連合全体で
対処すべき問題だしね。
By rights, the Shinobi Alliance
should deal with this problem.
うちが単独で調べていることが
連合に知れれば→
It'll be troublesome if
they find out that
we're independently
investigating this.
やっかいなことになります。
とはいえ 今 連合をあげて→
But taking action on
the Land of Silence
黙の国と事を構えるのも
まずいでしょ。
in the name of the alliance
will be touchy.
ようやく手にした
平和ですからね。
Just when we finally
achieved peace.
サイが黙の国に潜入すると
言い残してから もう２週間か。
It's already been two weeks
since Sai left word
that he was infiltrating
the Land of Silence, right?
このまま手をこまねいている
わけにはいきません。
We can't just stand by without
taking action any further.
やっと来たか。
It's finally here.
The state of affairs is more serious
than we previously thought.
(サイの声)
事態は予想以上に深刻です。
If the Land of Silence is left
to continue as is,
黙の国を野放しにすれば→
the Shinobi Alliance will
be threatened at some point.
いずれは
連合の脅威となるでしょう。
There is one leader
at work in this land.
この国は たった一人の
指導者によって動かされています。
その男の名は…。
His name is…
Gengo.
ゲンゴ。
初めて聞く名前だな。
I've never heard that name before.
It's possible,
he will become the one
(サイ)彼は忍という哀れな存在。
who may very well change
the pitiful existence of shinobi…
それどころか この世界の
枠組みそのものを変える→
In fact, he may change
the whole framework of this world.
存在になるかもしれません。
I don't even know
myself anymore…
僕はもう 自分が
わからなくなりはじめています。
This isn't good.
まずいっすね。
だよね。
Right?
Sai led a team of ten,
サイが率いていたのは
暗部の中でも→
comprised of the cream of
the crop among the ANBU.
屈指の実力者で
構成されたチームです。
It would take a formidable enemy
to wipe them out…
それが全滅となると
敵も相当の手だれ。
Probably…
だろうね。
サイの読みは正しかった。
Sai's instincts were right.
大戦の失踪者や
抜け忍たちの多くが→
Many of the shinobi who
disappeared after the Great War
黙の国にいるとみて
間違いないでしょう。
and Rogue Shinobi are
in the Land of Silence.
サイは無事かな？
I hope Sai is all right.
簡単に死ぬようなやつじゃ
ありません。 ですが…。
He's not one to get killed
so easily, but…
There are hints in
his message that sound
文面からにじみ出る
ゲンゴという男に対する→
like admiration for
this man named Gengo.
称賛にも似た執着。
You don't think Sai has…?
まさか サイのやつ…。
純粋だからね 彼は。
He's very pure hearted, so…
サイを救出し
黙の国の芽をつんでおく。
If we're to get Sai out of there
and nip the Land of Silence
in the bud…
となれば
取るべき道はひとつです。
we have just one option.
Could we be thinking
the same thing?
ひょっとして
俺と同じことを考えてる？
Yes.
はい。 ですが 火影様を
行かせるわけにはいきません。
However, you can't go.
Right…
だよね。
目立たず行動するには→
To go unnoticed,
a three-man squad will be best.
スリーマンセルが最適です。
Could you get two good shinobi
from the ANBU?
暗部から腕の立つのを
２名呼んでもらえますか？
スリーマンセル。 もう一人は誰か
心当たりあるの？
A three-man squad…
You already have someone in mind
for the third member?
我々のやろうとしていることは
連合への背信行為です。
What we're attempting is
a clear breach of faith
toward the alliance.
If worse comes to worst,
いざとなったら 切り捨てられる
人間でなければなりません。
we would have to disavow
any knowledge of this team.
俺が行きます。
I'll go.
You carry a big part of
the responsibilities within the alliance.
お前にだって連合の一翼を担う
役目があるんだ。
You can't…
それを いまさら…。
業務が１つ増えるだけです。
I'm simply adding another job
to my plate.
止めても無駄か。
It's useless to try to
stop you, isn't it?
Still, I would have thought
you'd pick Ino and Choji.
それにしても お前なら→
イノとチョウジを指名するかと
思ったけどね。
For this mission,
今回の任務に必要なのは
チャクラを操り→
we need someone who can
control chakra and can hide us.
こちらの存在を
隠すことができるタイプと→
実際に標的を
しとめる術を持った忍です。
And someone who has a jutsu
to make a direct hit on the target.
Besides…
それに…。
それに？
Besides?
あいつらには
あいつらの生活がありますから。
Those two have
their own lives now.
I think I know just
the ANBU for this.
暗部に格好の人間がいたな。
２人とも とっても
つきあいやすい連中だから→
They're both easy to work with…
きっと気にいると思うよ。
So I'm sure you'll like them.
あれ？ 先輩 出張っすか？
SHIKAMARU
What?
Going on a business trip, senpai?
ああ あとは頼むな。
Yeah, take care of things here
for me.
It must be nice!
いいな～
俺も行きたいくらいっすよ。
I wish I could go too!
Damn it.
はぁ～ ったく。
お土産 お願いしますよ。
Please bring me back a souvenir!
Yeah sure, I will.
あ～ わかった わかった。
This is Soku of the ANBU.
(カカシ)暗部の鏃だ。
(シカマル)つきあいやすい連中ねぇ。
Easy to work with, huh?
And where's the other one?
それで もう一人は？
(朧)ここにおります。
I am right here.
いつの間に？
彼は 朧だ。
When did you—?
He's Ro.
自分や他人のチャクラの量を
自由に操って→
He has the ability to freely manipulate
his own and others' chakra
気配を完全に消したり
別人になりすます能力がある。
to erase all signs of his presence
or become another person.
わかりやすく申し上げるならば→
If I were to put it simply,
it's a modification of
the chakra from
他者が知覚するという
観点においての変異にござる。
the point of view of
what others perceive.
対象人物のチャクラを実際に
増大させられるのではなく→
I do not actually increase
the chakra of the target,
知覚する側の錯誤を
生むのみにござりますな。
I create an anachronism
in their perception.
Like, that's even more confusing.
(鏃)余計わかりにくいし。
This one's still a kid.
こいつ まだガキじゃないですか。
心外だし。
Like, unthinkable, right?
In the world of shinobi,
ability is, like, everything.
忍の世界は実力がすべてだし。
言うね。
You don't mince words.
After the Academy,
ヒノコはアカデミーを出ると
すぐに才能を見込まれて→
we noticed Hinoko's talents
and scouted her for the ANBU.
暗部にスカウトされた。
She's only 14,
まだ14だが暗部内での信頼も厚い。
but she's already highly regarded
in the ANBU.
I asked you to like,
not to use my real name, Lord Hokage.
火影様
本名で呼ぶなって言ってるし。
お前 ヒノコってのか。
Your name's Hinoko?
ずいぶん かわいらしい名前…。
That's a really cute na—!
I, like, hate to be called that name.
その名前で呼ばれるのは
嫌いだし→
I'd like you to be careful
about that.
そこんとこは
気をつけてもらいたいし。
So, what can you do?
で 何ができるんだ？
My weapon is a chakra needle.
私の武器は チャクラの針。
Once my needle hones in
on a target,
私の針は一度狙いを定めたら→
it will not stop its pursuit until,
it like, pierces its target.
標的を貫くまで
どこまでも追っていくんだし。
Very suitable for assassination.
まさに 暗殺向きか。
無駄な殺生はしないし。
I don't like,
needlessly kill.
I pierced its chakra stimulation point,
今は チャクラ活性化のツボを貫いたから
さっきより何倍も元気だし。
so it's like, several times
more livelier now.
(シカマル)朧の術で潜入し→
We'll infiltrate using Ro's jutsu,
then I'll immobilize the target
with my Shadow Strangle Jutsu,
俺の影首縛りで
標的の動きを封じ→
鏃がしとめる。
まさに相乗効果。
and Soku will finish him.
A true collaboration indeed.
The synergy in this plan is ideal.
いわゆる シナジーが見込める
理想の組み合わせでござるな。
Like, that sounds tedious.
長ったらしいし。
They're exactly what you wanted.
シカマルの要望どおりだよ。
I have no objections…
不満はないんすが…。
なんだし？
Then, like, what's the issue?
その しぃしぃ言うの
なんとかなんねえのか？
Can you drop the "like" thing?
Like, absolutely not.
無理だし。
決まりだな。
Well, it's decided.
So once everything's ready—
じゃあ 準備が整いしだい…。
Would it be okay to leave
tomorrow morning?
出発は 明朝でもいいっすか？
また 将棋とか言わないよね？
It's not shogi again, is it?
I have some business
to take care of.
ちょっと 用があるんすよ。
(シカマル)んなわけで 帰るのは
少し先になりそうだから→
So anyway, looks like
SHIKAKU NARA
I'll be heading back a bit later,
so I won't be able to visit next month.
来月は来られねえかもな。
I have two subordinates under me.
この俺が
部下を２人も連れてだぜ？
It's not like me, huh?
柄じゃねえよな。
ASUMA SARUTOBI
我が身を捧げて守るものを
親父も あんたも持ってたっけ。
Both you and my dad had someone
you'd give your lives to protect.
But, I haven't found anyone
like that yet…
けど 俺には まだ…。
Big Brother Shika!
(ミライ)シカの兄ちゃ！
ミライ！
Mirai!
Big Brother Shika!
シカの兄ちゃ！
うわっと！
Whoa, there!
(紅)シカマルも忙しい身なんだから
毎月 来てくれなくてもいいのよ。
Shikamaru, you're so busy these days,
you don't need to
come every month.
そんなんじゃないですけど。
I'm not that busy.
この人 ベビーシッターさん。
ときどき ミライを見てもらっててね。
This is our babysitter.
She occasionally watches
Mirai for me.
どうも。
Hello.
He may not look it, but he's
Lord Hokage's right-hand man.
こう見えて 火影様の右腕なのよ。
よしてください。
Please…
Oh, I see!
そうなんですね。 すみません。
まだ よくわかってなくて…。
I'm sorry, I still don't know
these things yet.
彼女 里に移り住んだばかりなの。
She just started living here.
こうして
人の往来が盛んになったのも→
People are moving into
this village
all because of people like
you and the Lord Hokage.
あなたや火影様のおかげね。
とんでもない。
Please, don't mention it.
今の平和が
長く続くといいんだけど。
I hope this peace will last
for a long time.
ASUMA SARUTOBI
Big Brother!
兄ちゃ お花！
Flowers!
そうか。
お父さんに持ってきたのか？
Oh really?
You brought them for your daddy?
偉いな ミライは。
You're so clever, Mirai!
ミライは 本当に
シカマル兄ちゃんのことが大好きね。
Mirai, you really love
Big Brother Shikamaru, don't you?
うん！
Uh-huh!
続きますよ 平和。
This peace will last.
続けてみせます。
I'll make it last.
なんで 今頃になって…。
Why now?
クソ！ 縁起でもねえ…。
Damn it!
Such bad luck.
(ナルト)よう！ シカマルじゃねえか。
Hey, Shikamaru!
ずいぶん早起きだな。
You're up awfully early.
ナルト…。
Naruto…
お前こそ 早いじゃねえか。
I could say
the same about you.
I got up and couldn't
go back to sleep…
なんか
朝早く 目覚めちまったから→
I'm on my way home
from Ichiraku Ramen.
一楽で ラーメン食べた帰りなんだ。
That shop opens that early?
こんな早くからやってんのか
あの店。
It's open 24 hours now!
最近 24時間になったんだぜ。
だからって
朝っぱらから ラーメンかよ。
Yeah but, who eats ramen
for breakfast?
朝 昼 晩 オーケーだ！
I could eat it for breakfast,
lunch, and dinner.
俺の体の半分は
ラーメンでできている！
Half of my body's made of ramen!
ん？ あっ！ ニンニク臭かった？
Hmm?
Do I smell like garlic?
そうだ。
Oh…
これ 食えよ。
Chew this.
おぉ～！ 懐かしい…。
GUM
This brings back memories!
これ 大好きだってばよ。
I love this stuff!
じゃあな。
See ya.
Work?
仕事か？
あぁ ちょっとな。
Yeah, just a little.
お前も
ラーメンばっか食ってないで 働けよ。
Don't just sit around
and eat ramen.
Do some work.
どっかの誰かさんが→
Well, a certain someone somewhere
めんどくせぇ任務ばっか
持ってくっから 半年 休みなしだ。
keeps assigning me
annoying missions…
So I won't have a break
for the next six months.
お前にとって
今が いちばん大事なときなんだ。
This is the most critical time
in your life.
わかってるってばよ！ でもよ…。
I know that.
But you know—
でも じゃねえ！
No buts!
１つでも多くの任務をこなして→
Take on as many missions
as possible,
やっぱり ナルトでなければと
みんなに思わせるためだ。
make it so everyone says,
"It has to be Naruto,
no one else will do."
If you think
they acknowledge you now
大戦の英雄ってだけで
認められるほど甘くはないんだぜ。
because you're the hero
of the Great War, you're wrong.
Yeah, yeah.
はい はい。
おい ナルト。
– Hey, Naruto.
– Hmm?
ん？
You're going to become
the Hokage.
お前は火影になる男だ。
それを忘れんな。
Don't ever forget that.
まっすぐ 自分の言葉は曲げねえ。
それが 俺の忍道だ。
I never go back on my word.
That's my Ninja Way.
俺たちの だ。
You mean "our" way.
あぁ。
Yeah.
《ナルト… お前は いつまでも
今のままでいてくれ。
Naruto…
Always stay
just the way you are.
そのために 俺がいるんだからな》
That's the reason why
I'm here.
それじゃ ま…
お仕事といきますか。
Anyway…
I guess it's time to go to work.
I humbly guarantee that
we will be able to deceive
the enemy's eyes with this.
Like, if we kill all of the lookouts,
it will be easy to pass
through the checkpoint.
It would spell trouble
if we do that
and they found out
the Leaf's involved.
Don't underestimate the enemy.
If we linger too long,
we'll only like, up the chances
of the enemy noticing us.
Next time on Naruto Shippuden:
"Shikamaru's Story,
A Cloud Drifting in the Silent Dark,
Part 2: Dark Clouds"
Soku, trust me.